After 700 years of doing what he was built for,
he'll discover what he was meant for.
WALL·E is a animation, family, science fiction film directed by Andrew Stanton.
What if mankind had to leave Earth and somebody
forgot to turn the last robot off?
After hundreds of years doing what he was built for, WALL•E discovers a new
purpose in life when he meets a sleek search robot named EVE.
EVE comes to realize that WALL•E has inadvertently stumbled upon the key to the
planet's future, and races back to space to report to the humans.
Meanwhile, WALL•E chases EVE across the galaxy and sets into motion one of the
most imaginative adventures ever brought to the big screen.
WALL·E / M-O (voice), played by Ben Burtt.
EVE (voice), played by Elissa Knight.
Captain (voice), played by Jeff Garlin.
Shelby Forthright, BnL CEO, played by Fred Willard.
John (voice), played by John Ratzenberger.
Mary (voice), played by Kathy Najimy.
WALL-E (stylized with an interpunct as WALL·E) is a 2008 American animated romantic science fiction film directed by
Andrew Stanton, who co-wrote the screenplay with Jim Reardon, based on a story by Stanton and Pete Docter.
Produced by Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures, the film stars the voices of Ben Burtt, Elissa Knight, Jeff
Garlin, John Ratzenberger, Kathy Najimy, and Sigourney Weaver, with Fred Willard in a live-action role.
The film follows a solitary robot named WALL-E on a future,
uninhabitable, deserted Earth in 2805, left to clean up garbage.
He is visited by a robot called EVE sent from the starship Axiom, with
whom he falls in love and pursues across the galaxy.
After directing Finding Nemo, Stanton felt Pixar had created believable simulations of
underwater physics and was willing to direct a film set largely in space.
WALL-E has minimal dialogue in its early sequences; many of the characters in the film do not have voices,
but instead communicate with body language and robotic sounds that were designed by Burtt.
The film incorporates various topics including consumerism, corporatocracy, nostalgia, waste management, human
environmental impact and concerns, obesity/sedentary lifestyles, and global catastrophic risk.
It is also Pixar's first animated film with segments
featuring live-action characters.
Thomas Newman composed the film's musical score.
The film cost $180 million to produce, a record-breaking
sum for an animated film at the time.
Following Pixar tradition, WALL-E was paired with a short
film titled Presto for its theatrical release.
WALL-E premiered at the Greek Theatre in Los Angeles on June 23,
2008, and was released in the United States on June 27.
The film received critical acclaim for its animation, story, voice acting, characters, visuals,
score, sound design, screenplay, use of minimal dialogue, and scenes of romance.
It was also commercially successful, grossing $521.3 million worldwide
and becoming the ninth-highest grossing film of 2008.
It won the 2008 Golden Globe Award for Best Animated Feature Film, the 2009 Hugo Award for Best Long Form Dramatic Presentation, the final Nebula Award for
Best Script, the Saturn Award for Best Animated Film and the Academy Award for Best Animated Feature with five additional Oscar nominations.
The film was widely named by critics and organizations, including the National Board of Review and American Film
Institute, as one of the best films of 2008, and is considered among the greatest animated films ever made.
In 2021, WALL-E became the second Pixar feature film (after Toy Story), as well as the second animated film in the 21st century after Shrek, to be selected for
preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
In September 2022, at the request of Stanton, Disney licensed WALL-E to The Criterion Collection, which re-released the film as a special
edition 4K Blu-Ray-standard Blu-ray combo pack on November 22, 2022, marking the first Pixar film to ever receive such an honor.
The film explores themes of garbage, dystopia, space
travel, distant future, loneliness.
The tone is thought_provoking.